Finding Aid for Observatory (University of Michigan) records, 1855-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs
  The Photographs series (1908-1963; 1 linear ft.) consists of photographs (including oversize photos) documenting the University of Michigan observatories. These include images of buildings, observatories, telescopes, faculty, staff, benefactors and visitors. An oversize group photograph of the 46th meeting of the American Astronomical Society at the Perkins Observatory in Delaware, Ohio includes Dean McLaughlin, Orrin Mohler, and Hazel Losh.
  - Buildings, Observatories, and telescopes
    - East Hall, site of new astronomy building 1961 (Box 16)
    - Lamont-Hussey Observatory, undated 1925 (Box 16)
    - Lamont-Hussey Observatory (Box 16)
    - Lamont Telescope (27 in. refractor), temporary mounting in Ann Arbor 1925 (Box 16)
    - McGregor Fund 2.5 meter disk, never used, removed from Observatory, ca. 1946 (Box 16)
    - McMath-Hulbert Observatory
      - Exterior views (also oversize photo) (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous Equipment (Box 16)
      - Telescopes and spectroheliograph (Box 16)
    - McMath Telescope (24 in. reflector) (Box 16)
    - Observatory (Ann Arbor, Michigan) (Box 16)
    - Portage Lake Observatory (Box 16)
    - Radio Telescope, ca. 1951 (Box 16)
    - South Pier-37" Reflector U of M Observatory 1908 (Box 16)
  - Faculty, Staff, Benefactors and Visitors
    - Bennett, Clif, retirement party 1960 (Box 16)
    - Brunnow, Franz F. (Box 16)
    - Curtis, Heber D. (Box 16)
      (also oversize photo)
    - Curtiss, Ralph H. (Box 16)
    - Goldberg, Leo (Box 16)
    - Hall, Asaph (Box 16)
    - Harrington, Mark W. (Box 16)
    - Hulbert, Henry S. (Box 16)
    - Lamont, Robert P., and family (Box 16)
    - McMath, Francis C. (Box 16)
    - McMath, Robert R.
      - Bear hunting trophies (Box 16)
      - Groups (Box 16)
        (also oversize photos, Box 17)
      - Interamerican Scientific Conference, Mexico City February 1942 (Box 16)
      - Portraits, formal and informal (Box 16)
    - Mohler, Orren (Wertzaprung Symposium) 1964 (Box 16)
    - Prince, Helen Dodson (Box 16)
    - Eclipse expedition to Fryeburg, Maine 1932 (Box 16)
    - Groups (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Observatories
    - Foreign (Box 16)
    - United States (Box 16)
  - Observation Photos
    (also outsize photos, Box 17)
    - Comets, Moon (Box 16)
    - Sun (Box 16)
  - Albums
    - The McMath-Hulbert Observatory 1941 (outsize) (Box 16)
    - Dedication of Robert R. McMath Solar Telescope, Kitt Peak National Observatory 1962 (Box 16)
    - A portfolio of photographs taken with the Heber D. Curtis Schmidt Telescope circa 1952 (Box 16)
      (includes photographs of Portage Lake Observatory and the Curtis Telescope)
    - Untitled circa 1964 (Box 16)
      (includes copy photographs of the Observatory in Ann Arbor, 1920-1963 Portage Lake Observatory, Peach Mountain Radio telescope, and the Physics-Astronomy Building)
- Outsize Unbound Material
  - Meteorological Observations, Ypsilanti and Ann Arbor 1859-1903 (Box 17)
  - Photographs, 1 folders (Box 17)
  - Portrait of James Craig Watson (Box 17)
  - Eclipse Photographs 1952-1970 (Box 18)
  - Spectroheliograms 1938-1938 (Box 18)
  - McMath-Hulbert Observatory 1930-1940, undated (Box 18)
  - Expeditions 1925-1932 (Box 18)
- Outsize Bound Material
  - Album: The McMath-Hulbert Observatory of the University of Michigan 1941 (Volume BImu/C455)
- Blueprints
  The final series, Blueprints (1907-1967) contains over 350 oversize architectural plans and mechanical drawings of university observatories and telescopes. The bulk of the drawings are from the period 1907-1911 and document the 36 inch reflecting telescope in the Detroit Observatory. Other material documents the McMath-Hulbert Observatory, the Lamont Refractor, and the Peach Mountain Observatory.
  (Filed in Blueprint Drawers)
  - Detroit Observatory
    - Building Plans (mainly 1908 addition), 1907-1909, 19 drawings (Map-case 126)
    - Reflecting Telescope 1907-1909, 45 drawings (Map-case 126)
    - Original Mechanical Drawings 1907-1910, 29 drawings (Map-case 126)
    - Misc. and "N" Series 1907-1911, 42 drawings (Map-case 126)
    - "R" Series 1907-1910, 39 drawings water damaged (Map-case 126)
    - "S" Series 1907-1910, 38 drawings (Map-case 126)
    - "T" Series 1907-1909, 26 drawings (Map-case 126)
    - Spectrograph 1909-1921, 23 drawings (Map-case 126)
  - Lamont Refractor 1910-1911, 31 drawings (Map-case 126)
  - McMath-Hulbert Observatory 1956-1957, 37 drawings (Map-case 126)
  - Peach Mountain/Portage Lake (including Stinchfield Woods) 1948-1968, 45 drawings (Map-case 126)
  - Miscellaneous Blueprints, 16 drawings
    - Angell Hall 15" Telescope 1928, 4 drawings (Map-case 126)
    - Base Lake Site 1919 undated, 3 drawings (Map-case 126)
    - Century Detroit Proposed Telescope 1967 (Map-case 126)
    - Kitt Peak 36" Telescope--Layout of Dome and Cut-Off Angles 1966 (Map-case 126)
    - McMath Estate (Lake Angelus, MI) 1950 (Map-case 126)
    - Mechanical Department Observatorio Nacional de la Plata 1912 (Map-case 126)
    - Proposed UM 75" Reflector 1929 (Map-case 126)
    - RAO Laboratory (Radio Astronomy/Space Research Building) 1967 (Map-case 126)
    - Schmidt Telescope 1940 (Map-case 126)
    - Subdivision Plan for Mr. A.F. Smith 1910 (Map-case 126)
    - Temperature Case, Reflecting Telescope 1927 (Map-case 126)